Coded Bias is a documentary film directed by Shalini Kantayya.
Exploring the fallout of MIT Media Lab researcher Joy Buolamwini's startling discovery that facial recognition does not
see dark-skinned faces accurately, and her journey to push for the first-ever legislation in the U.S.
to govern against bias in the algorithms that impact us all.
Self, played by Joy Buolamwini.
Self, played by Cathy O'Neil.
Self, played by Meredith Broussard.
Self, played by Silkie Carlo.
Self, played by Virginia Eubanks.
Self, played by Ravi Naik.
Coded Bias is an American documentary film directed by Shalini
Kantayya that premiered at the 2020 Sundance Film Festival.
The film includes contributions from researchers Joy Buolamwini, Deborah Raji, Meredith Broussard, Cathy
O’Neil, Zeynep Tufekci, Safiya Noble, Timnit Gebru, Virginia Eubanks, and Silkie Carlo, and others.
The film explores themes of artificial intelligence (a.i.),
silicon valley, civil rights, sexism, racism.
The tone is dark.